## **ABOUT ME**

Well experienced in the field of Cloud Computing, Electronics, IoT, Web Development, App Development, Communication Systems and Sensor Networks. Hardworking, sincere and has never failed to meet deadlines. Have a passion for acquiring new skills while mastering existing skills.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Samsung PRISM Project
Project Intern, (December 2019 – August 2020)
Edgate Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (TI University Program)
Intern, (June 2019 – July 2019)
International Society of Automation, VIT
Technical Lead, (April 2019 – May 2020)
International Society of Automation, VIT

### **EDUCATION**

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore (July 2017 – Present)

Core Member, (December 2017 – April 2019)

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering with specialization in IoT and Sensors | 8.88

St. Alphonsa English Medium School, Calicut (June 2014 - June 2016)
C.B.S.E. SENIOR SECONDARY EXAMINATION | 87.4%

St. Alphonsa English Medium School, Calicut (June 2004 - June 2014)
C.B.S.E. SECONDARY EXAMINATION | 10.00

# **MAJOR CERTIFICATIONS**

D0081x: Fundamentals of Containers, Kubernetes, and Red Hat OpenShift

Issued By: Red Hat on EdX (b3fd4a6a13dc441a9c537fa75b05dfa8)

Architecting with Google Kubernetes Engine Issued By: Google Cloud on Coursera (RRYPC5WKPM2N)



# Sharath Cherian Thomas

Oonnukallel, Chembukadave, Kodenchery, Kozhikode, Kerala, India. 673580

(+91)9048611293

sharathct22@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sharathct22 github.com/thesct22 hub.docker.com/u/thesct22

#### **PROGRAMING LANGUAGES**

C C++ Python Java

Embedded C MATLAB SQL

SKILLS

Google Cloud Platform Docker

Raspberry Pi Android Studio

**MERN Stack** 

Kubernetes

Architecting with Google Compute Engine

Issued By: Google Cloud on Coursera (EWTXKF9Z7EJC)

Cloud Engineering with Google Cloud

Issued By: Google Cloud on Coursera (EU5KDXZPPP3D)

Industrial IoT on Google Cloud Platform

Issued By: Google Cloud on Coursera (9N9AJ7L34AQJ)

Java for Android

Issued By: Vanderbilt University on Coursera (4VV3BNW6HTA7)

# **MAJOR PROJECTS**

Containerized Social Media Website Using MERN Stack

https://github.com/thesct22/thotappFrontend

https://github.com/thesct22/thotappBackend

http://34.67.228.107.xip.io/

Monitoring of air-conditioned warehouses

https://github.com/thesct22/Centralized-AC-Monitoring

Theft and violence detection

https://github.com/thesct22/The-Watcher

Pickman

https://github.com/thesct22/Pickman

3D Plotting on Bokeh Server using GCP

https://github.com/thesct22/3dplot

Health Monitoring of Industrial Machines

https://github.com/thesct22/Health-Monitoring

https://github.com/thesct22/Motor-Health

Mobile App with Firebase integration and WebView for 3D Plotting

https://github.com/eknooroberoi/Air-Condition-App

## **MERITS & AWARDS**

- Paper got accepted for international conference (ICASIC'20) held in February 2020 and will be published through Springer Proceedings.
- Paper got accepted and will be published in IJEET (Scopus indexed) journal.
- Won IEEE Techloop 2019, conducted in VIT, Vellore in the month of March 2019.
- Finalist in IoT Challenge 2019, conducted in IIT Bombay in March 2019.
- Finalist in iAct 2019, conducted by ISA, Bangalore in March 2019.
- Finalist in Hack Off v2.0, conducted by IET-VIT in December 2019.

#### **MISCELLANEOUS**

LabVIEW Bash Arduino IDE

MSP430 Code Composer Studio

**Communication Protocols** 

Git